var questions = [{
	question: "Which Gators legend is not part of Florida's Ring of Honer?",
	choices: ["Tim Tebow", "Steve Spurrier", "Emmitt Smith", "Wilbur Marshall"],
	correctAnswer: "Tim Tebow",
}, {
	question: "When was the last time that the Florida vs. Georgia game did not take place in Jacksonville?",
	choices: ["1990", "1993", "1995", "1997"],
	correctAnswer: "1995",
}, {
	question: "Historically, what school is the University of Florida's main rival?",
	choices: ["University of Central Florida", "Ohio State University", "University of Georgia", "Florida State University"],
	correctAnswer: "Florida State University",
}, {
	question: "In what year did the Florida Gators win their first National Title?",
	choices: ["1965", "1912", "1996", "2004"],
	correctAnswer: "1996",
}, {
	question: "Which member of the 2007 Florida Gators was a Heisman Trophy winner?",
	choices: ["Tim Tebow", "Dorian Munroe", "Jamar Hornsby", "Jeremy Finch"],
	correctAnswer: "Tim Tebow",
}, {
	question: "Florida beat Florida State in which bowl game at the end of the 1996 season to secure the National Championship?",
	choices: ["Rose Bowl", "Sugar Bowl", "Fiesta Bowl", "Orange Bowl"],
	correctAnswer: "Sugar Bowl",
}, {
	question: "Which Florida head coach never beat Florida State in Tallahassee, Florida?",
	choices: ["Ron Zook", "Will Muschamp", "Urban Meyer", "Steve Spurrier"],
	correctAnswer: "Steve Spurrier",
}, {
	question: "What is the name of the alligator mascot of the Florida Gators?",
	choices: ["Alex E. Gator", "Albert E. Gator", "Alvin E. Gator", "Allie E. Gator"],
	correctAnswer: "Albert E. Gator",
}, {
	question: "In what year did Florida Gators football celebrate its 100th anniversary?",
	choices: ["1975", "1988", "2006", "2010"],
	correctAnswer: "2006",
}, {
	question: "The all-time career passing yards leader in Florida history is:",
	choices: ["Chris Leak", "Rex Grossman", "Shane Matthews", "Tim Tebow"],
	correctAnswer: "Chris Leak",
}];


  $('#start').click(function() {
    $("#questions").fadeIn();
    $(this).hide();
  });

var currentQuestion = 0;
var correctAnswers = 0;
var incorrectAnswers = 0;



$("#timerStarts").hide();
$(".submitAnswer").hide();
$(".gameReset").hide();
$("#correctAnswers").hide();
$("#incorrectAnswers").hide();

function checkAnswer () { 
	for (var i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {
		var userChoice = $("input[name = 'question-" + i +"']:checked");
		if (userChoice.val() == questions[i].correctAnswer) {
			correctAnswers++; 

			} else {
				incorrectAnswers++;
				
		}
	}
	$("#correctAnswers").append(" " + correctAnswers);
	$("#incorrectAnswers").append(" " + incorrectAnswers); 
};


function timer() {
	var seconds = 60;
	counter = setInterval (function() {
	$("#timerStarts").html('<h2> Time Remaining:' + seconds-- + '</h2>');
		if (seconds === -1) {
			$("#timerStarts").html("<h2> Out of Time! </h2>");
			clearInterval(counter);
			function delayScore(){
				$("#showQuestions").hide();
				$("#timerStarts").hide();
				$(".submitAnswer").hide();
				checkAnswer();
				$("#correctAnswers").show();
				$("#incorrectAnswers").show();
			}
			setTimeout(delayScore, 1000);
		}
	}, 1000);
	
};

$(".gameStart").on("click", function() {
	$(".gameStart").hide();
	displayCurrentQuestion();
	$("#timerStarts").show();
	timer();
});

function displayCurrentQuestion() {
	$(".submitAnswer").show();
	for (var i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {
		$("#showQuestions").append("<h3>" + questions[i].question + "</h3>");
		for (var j = 0; j < questions[i].choices.length; j++) {
			$("#showQuestions").append('<input type="radio" name="question'  + '-' + i + '" value="'+ questions[i].choices[j] + '"> '+ questions[i].choices[j] );

		}
	}
	$(".submitAnswer").on("click", function() {
		$("#showQuestions").hide();
		$("#timerStarts").hide();
		$(".submitAnswer").hide();
		checkAnswer();
		clearInterval(counter);
		$("#correctAnswers").show();
		$("#incorrectAnswers").show();
		$(".gameReset").show();
	});
	$(".gameReset").on("click",function() {
		window.location = "index.html"
    })
};





   










